Downloaded @ subs4free.club
This story is a replica
of the original.
Ready?
Huh?
One, two, three!
One!
One, two!
One, two, three, four!
Juan always said he didn't believe
anything from History class.
Or books, for that matter.
How could they be so sure
what Hernan Cortes thought...
...or Montezuma,
or Alexander the Great?
He said it was all made up.
He said no one could know
why someone did what they did...
...except for the person
who did it.
And more often than not,
not even them.
Water.
Skies crisscrossed by clouds.
Silent mountains.
Elements controlled by Tlaloc.
For centuries, the 300 A.D. monolith
slumbered in a ravine.
Juan told me about the time
when some engineers...
...took the god Tlaloc
away from his home.
People were angry and sad,
but they took him anyway.
Without asking for permission
or forgiveness.
On the huge platform
powered by 860 hp...
...the god's transportation
took place over two stages.
From the shores of Texcoco Lake
to the Chapultepec Forest.
Power and telephone cables
had to be removed along the way.
And all because
they had to fill...
...the new anthropology museum
with old things.
The city was lit up...
...as Tlaloc traversed it
in his immortal slumber.
Witnessing the centuries-old
journey of the god...
...hundreds of thousands
watched in awe and curiosity.
- Photo!
- Stop it, stop.
- Get down.
- Oh, sweetie.
Soon after the museum opened,
Juan's father...
...took Juan to see Tlaloc
and told him about the plunder.
- Honey, please smile.
- I'm smiling.
Juan was five years old.
- Smile, Juan! Show your teeth!
- He never forgot the story.
"Death is our eternal companion"
"Always to our left"
"An arm's distance away"
The first time I visited the museum,
back in eighth grade...
...I had to copy the captions
next to the pieces...
...and get my notebook stamped
to prove I had been there.
I heard stories about
the creation, and wars...
...and about the things
that used to be here.
"It whispers in your ear
You felt its icy touch"
"The way you felt it today"
But I don't remember
any of it.
"It has always been
Watching over you"
"And it always will"
Next piece, please.
Turn it off.
Juan.
Juan!
- Turn off the light!
- Sorry, sorry.
The year of the earthquake,
Juan spent the summer...
...working at the museum
to pay for his weed.
Every day for three months
they took photographs...
...of each object
at the Maya room.
And it seemed
they'd never finish.
Rotate it counterclockwise,
please.
What are you doing?
No touching without gloves!
Juan, if you touch a piece again,
I'm sending you home.
Juan used to say it was impossible
to know how things start...
...we can only know
how they end...
...once they've ended.
I don't know if those photos
were the beginning of it all.
I don't know.
Where does an idea begin?
Who can tell?
MUSEUM
Wilson.
- Shoot.
- I said no.
- I don't want to.
- Shoot.
- Cut it out.
Ciudad Satelite,
23 km from Mexico City.
Shoot!
- Shoot, you bastard!
- I'm leaving.
- First we finish this, I told you how.
- I'm taking my Dad to the doctor.
- Either shoot or stand here.
- I don't want to, I'm serious.
Alexander the Great had
diamond-tipped arrows made for him.
They could go through
a Mongol's head.
These arrows couldn't
puncture a cat's head...
...but they'll pierce the cube.
But what's the point?
I need to know
I can trust you.
You can.
- What are you doing, asshole?
- You moved!
- You could've hit me in the eye!
- You told me to do it!
- What happened?
- Nothing.
- Wilson shot at my head.
- Why did you shoot at his head?
- It's not true.
- I thought I could trust you.
- You can.
- So, why did you shoot at me?
- Why did you shoot at him?
I didn't.
Shorty, they're fighting out there.
Lalo doesn't want to pay.
Who said you could
call me that?
I'd go out if I were you,
Shorty.
- I thought I could trust you.
- You can.
So why did you shoot me
in the head?
THE HARD LIFE OF AN EASY WOMAN
Can I borrow it?
No, Scherezada Rios stays here.
It's a hard one to find.
All right, if you don't pay,
you can't play.
What's up, Lalo?
Lalo has been playing
and hasn't paid yet.
Pay up, Lalo, don't be a dick.
Oh, you don't want to pay?
In that case, move it.
Move aside, let me--
Is that level 15?
Wait a minute.
I'll cover you.
But just this once, got it?
We can't set a precedent, Camila.
This isn't a game, fuckers.
We must think like the enemy.
As if we came from another planet.
When King Pakal returns in his ship
and everything comes to an end...
...don't say I didn't warn you,
you little shits.
- Juan, you're still here?
- No!
They're waiting for you!
- Ben, are you staying for dinner?
- I can't, my dad needs me.
- How is he doing?
- Good, they put him on oxygen.
I'm really sorry.
Give him one of the fruitcakes.
- My daughter made them.
- Don't use English words, Mom.
You can say fruitcake
in Spanish, you know?
Julio is waiting for you.
It's about the--
The Santa costume?
- I don't want to, Mom.
- Juan, come here.
No, Juan, I keep tucking it in,
but it's still too big on you.
It's hard to believe you are
Dr. Juan's grandson.
You should dress as an elf,
it would fit you better.
They've informed us that
the Modern Art Museum...
...and the Anthropology Museum
will remain closed...
...from today until
January 5th...
...while a new ventilation system
is being installed.
They're working day and night
to be ready when school starts.
So, this holiday season
there will be no museums.
- Can I use your phone?
- Wait, don't move yet.
- Let me finish.
- It's fine like this.
Put it on Mom's tab!
GUARDHOUSE
ACETONE
HARDWARE STORE
- Duct tape?
- Yes, duct tape.
- How many nails?
- A bunch.
- Thin copper wire, six meters.
- Six meters copper wire.
That's too much.
- Alligators?
- What are those?
Oh, the crocodiles!
Yes, I'll take a few.
- Do you have any acetone?
- What?
Ether?
Since Juan was a kid,
every Christmas...
...his grandfather dressed as Santa
and gave out presents after dinner.
He died that year, so everyone
agreed Juan would take over.
Juan protested, saying he'd rather
dress as Quetzalcoatl...
...because Santa Claus was a tool
to indoctrinate kids into capitalism.
His protests went ignored.
Take a deep breath.
Get dressed.
Your blood pressure
and resting heart rate are high.
- I'm prescribing you some pills.
- You did that already.
Hey, Dad...
I need to use your car,
can I borrow it?
I have something important to do
after Christmas dinner.
What are we going to do
with you, bud?
I already paid the deposit
for the place at the mall.
- I'm pretty much set to go.
- You're not a veterinarian yet.
I know that.
I'm graduating soon.
- I'm not like Uncle Oscar.
- Did you pick up the suit?
Yeah, I even got it tailored.
It's going to fit great.
Dad?
Am I dying soon, Dad?
Yes?
Yes, sweetie, show her in.
So I guess I'll see you
tonight, yeah?
You'll be there, right?
- I just filled the tank.
- Thanks.
- Thank you.
- Hey, Chiva.
- Time for your annual drug test?
- Anal, yes. Pretty wild.
Try it, you might like it.
- Dad said work calls only.
- What? What did Dad say?
- What did he say?
- Let go of me, asshole.
- Hello?
- Wilson?
Where have you been all day?
It has to be tonight.
What?
What do you mean "what"?
- But it's Christmas.
- So?
- You said the 31st.
- It has to be tonight.
- You said New Year's Eve.
- I just saw the news.
Repairs start tomorrow,
it's going to be crowded.
- It has to be tonight.
- Are we even ready?
Sure we're ready,
we've gone over and over it.
I already called Bosco,
I got the car, everything.
Yeah, but I can't tonight.
I'm having dinner with Dad.
I'm not asking, moron.
I'm not asking you to fucking prom.
You're coming tonight.
I guess we'll have to see
because...
...the doctor said it might be
his last Christmas.
Look, I'll see you at midnight
at the usual place.
Yes, Juan.
Don't be late.
We'll see.
Hello?
- What are you up to, Shorty?
- Nothing.
Eeny, meeny, miney, mo.
Catch a tiger by the toe.
If he hollers, let him go.
One, two, three, four...
One, two...
Why don't you hide here?
Get under the table.
No one will find you.
I saw you, under the chair!
You're mistaken,
there's no one here.
Hey, have you met
Oscar's girlfriend?
- He has a girlfriend?
- Why else ask for another seat?
- What?
- There's no more ham.
Don't fill up with snacks.
Wait a little.
Have some cheese and olives.
Don't fill up before dinner.
- She's his student!?
- We'll meet her soon.
- What is this stuff?
- It's pâté, thank you very much.
Hello! Merry Christmas!
This is Gaby.
Gaby, my family.
- Who's your guest?
- This is Gaby.
- Introduce us.
- Hello.
- My brother.
- Nice to meet you.
- Uncle Oscar, how are you?
- I'm fine.
I'll take your bag.
- Hi, nice to meet you.
- The lady of the house.
- My niece.
- Susana!
- It's Christmas, they're dating.
- Precisely, it's Christmas!
Good evening, sir.
I brought bread and cider.
This one has a bite mark!
- Neto was hungry.
- Must've been the baker!
- Did you taste that one, too!
- No, it's unopened!
- Really, it is!
- He says it's unopened.
Shorty, where are you going
with those bags?
- It's your kids, chopped up.
- Asshole.
- I'm dumping them in the dam.
- Don't joke about that!
- What do you want, chipmunk?
- Dad asked why you're here...
...instead of downstairs,
with everyone.
Why do you always
isolate yourself?
- Aren't you happy?
- It's Christmas, why would I be happy?
You should be thankful,
you have a family.
- Some people don't, but you do.
- Thank you, family.
Are you doing grandpa's thing?
Did the suit fit you?
I bet it didn't.
It was too big on you.
I'm sure it looks huge on you.
If it was green instead,
you'd be a nice elf.
If you do it, do it right.
It's very important you do it right.
- Don't screw up.
- You smell like period blood.
You smell like baby shit,
you fucking dwarf.
Make way for the turkey!
Give an applause
to the cook!
Everyone, hush!
- Please, sit down.
- Children, sit down!
I just want to say...
...that this has been
a terrible year.
I want you to join me in a toast
to someone very special...
...to my father.
Thank you, cheers!
- Cheers, cheers.
- To grandpa!
- To grandpa.
- And to your joy as well.
And to the joys
this year brought us!
...its scales will dry up.
No, Keiko means "lucky one,"
it doesn't bring you luck.
So kids can see it!
It was in Sea Wo--
- It was in Sea World, right?
- Norway.
- It was in Norway.
- In the sea.
- Norway?
- Yeah, right?
It's so that people
can have a good time.
We went there recently.
We loved it, it was great.
But he was asking why
bring it now?
It definitely has to be
a smoke screen.
The park can do whatever
they like with their money.
- It's a private company.
- The government can't interfere.
But how can you deny
state involvement...
...if they closed up
the freeway...
...so that two huge trucks could
move the orca to the park...
- ...before its scales dried up?
- Whales don't have scales.
- Got it?
- Having fun in the Pacific...
...and waking up in Mexico City
is not good luck.
But why do it now?
Why, at this point for the country,
with the peso as low as it is...
...and ties between the cartels
and the government?
- Enlighten us, Juan.
- Juan, do you know about orcas?
- What?
- About orcas, like Keiko.
Hey, Christmas, right here!
We're having a conversation.
Don't worry, you can go
play Atari with the kids...
...while the rest of us grown ups
talk about politics.
- Keiko will die there.
- It will?
Then, they'll chop him up
and sell him outside the park.
Yeah, fish tacos!
Did you know they live
with their mothers?
All their lives,
especially males.
- They stay with their moms.
- So you're an orca?
Is your thesis about whales,
Shorty?
It's been nine years.
Wait, he's been doing
field practice for nine years...
...and his dissertation
is about masturbation.
- What? Tell them.
- What will the title be?
Are you leaving?
- Don't go!
- What's the title?
"Masturbatory habits
in Ciudad Satelite."
- It's Christmas, can't we have fun?
- But he started it!
We're all having fun!
- What?
- Shorty, it's time for the family picture.
I know, I'm coming.
Give me a minute.
Hey, would you like to see
something spectacular?
You would?
- Know where Santa's presents are?
- Where?
Right here.
You're lying.
Look.
Let's see here.
Do you see this?
This one's for Iker,
this one's for Pilar.
This one's for you, Lalo!
Should we open it?
A Millennium Falcon!
What a lucky kid!
Isn't it great?
I saw your mom come in
and leave them here.
Do you know what
that means?
All right, then.
Think about it.
Santa's coming soon. Whoever is
not in the photo gets no present.
- You won't fit in the frame!
- Nephew, come here.
Did I tell you about the fire
at your grandparents' house?
Only about a hundred times.
She doesn't know this one,
so act surprised.
This ingrate's grandparents,
meaning my parents...
...had a house in Novelist St.
It was really cool!
It was a modernist house,
one of the biggest in Satelite.
It was actually built by
Mario Pani in the '50s...
...back when all this
was empty hills.
Hey, what's going on?
Are you in a hurry?
Just tell the story already.
Why do I love this one
if he's so rude?
Wow!
- Cool!
- These are Legos!
- It's the one I wanted!
- Yes! Battleship!
I can make a polar bear!
What's all this?
What's going on, Pilar?
You're the oldest,
what happened?
- Juan.
- Juan told Lalo to open the gifts.
- He said they were here.
- Eduardo, come here!
Come here!
Give me that.
What did Juan tell you?
He said the presents were here
and we could open them.
- And you told everyone?
- He said I could.
- Was that nice?
- No.
Don't you laugh
or I'll smack your mouth!
Anyway, back in 1959,
that house burned down.
The ground floor was lost,
furniture, curtains, all of it.
We were in pajamas on the street,
watching it go up in flames.
The fire department came,
so did the police.
They even wrote about it
in the newspaper.
And do you know
why it burned down?
- You left the stereo on.
- That's the official version.
What actually happened
was entirely different.
- You bastard!
- Hey, Adriana!
Mom, your son told my kids
that Santa's not real...
...and where we hid
the presents!
- No, I didn't.
- Are you serious?
- Yes, you did!
- I didn't "say" it.
- I didn't tell him!
- You're a fucking moron!
- You fucking moron!
- Hey, hey, calm down.
Do you even know how much
Santa means to them?
- Listen to me!
- Enough of that! Stop!
When Juan left that night,
he never returned again.
Someone who looked like him
came back, but it wasn't him.
Good girl, yes you are.
Where's this moron?
Where is this moron?
Since we were kids,
Juan and I had our usual place.
Only we knew where
the usual place was.
- Where have you been?
- You said midnight sharp.
I was at the usual place
at midnight sharp.
I thought you weren't coming.
- Yes, Juan, I'm here.
- I see that.
When we got into college,
an old friend of Juan's...
...called Pepe Soto
took us out to celebrate.
On the way back,
Juan stopped at that sign...
...and painted the name
of our profession.
He said it was insulting that
there was even an Actors St...
...and not a single street in Satelite
to honor our noble field.
VETERINARIANS
Here.
Merry Christmas.
The Night of the Mayas.
Thanks, Juan.
I saw your dad through the window,
he looked better.
What time will we get
back home?
Don't start with that.
From this point on,
there's no turning back.
Yes, Juan.
We're no longer like
our stupid families.
Yes.
No one has ever
done this before.
Do you understand?
Yes, Juan.
You told me
I could trust you.
You can.
I know.
Let's go.
Wilson!
Go, go, go.
This stinks like ass.
Make do, Wilson.
Are you sure?
I am.
Eighty percent.
Sixty percent.
- There's no alarm, trust me.
- How could there not be?
The headdress, too?
No.
Someone beat us to it.
The original... is in Austria.
Do we care?
Stop it, stop.
What happened?
It's Pakal.
- What?
- It's Pakal!
Juan?
Juan, are you OK?
What's going on, man?
Just breathe.
Juan, just breathe.
We're almost out.
Do you realize, Wilson?
Benjamin, do you realize?
Did you ever imagine?
Did you ever imagine!?
We fucking rule!
We fucking rule, Wilson!
- I have to pee.
- We fucking rule!
I have to pee.
We're almost there, Wilson!
- I have to pee.
- Hold it.
- I have to pee right now.
- Wilson, hey!
What the fuck are you doing?!
Wilson!
I've always wanted
to do this.
Look at you,
fucking Wilson!
Do you realize?
You're the king of Satelite!
I mean, we both are.
We are the Aztec kings
of Naucalpan.
Wow.
- So?
- So what?
- Now what?
- Now, we celebrate.
But we're taking them to Bosco
so he can sell them, right?
He did tell you he could
sell them, didn't he?
- Is that all you care about?
- Is it true?
Shit, just let me enjoy this.
You sound like my dad.
Sorry, Juan.
But, did he?
So that's the official version about
the fire at your grandparents'.
But what really happened...
...was something
entirely different.
Your dad had met your mother
shortly before the fire.
He never disobeyed our dad,
except in those days.
He went rebellious on us.
That night...
...while everyone slept,
he brought her home.
Right there in the living room,
what better place, right?
And then he... you know.
Your mother has always been
a very attractive woman.
Anyway, long story short,
once he finished banging her...
...he forgot to put out the candles
he had lit to set the mood.
And when he came back,
the living room was on fire.
His first thought was to wake me,
looking scared shitless...
...and that's when...
...when we agreed
I'd take the blame for it.
I called the fire department
and we woke everyone up.
Why?
Back then, I was always
playing my Bach records...
...and I always forgot
to turn off the stereo.
Dad used to get angry,
he said it would catch fire...
...so no one ever
questioned the story.
Besides, well...
...by then I had already
dropped out of school...
...and had gone in and out
of the hospital.
I had even gotten Nelly
pregnant.
No one expected
anything else from me...
...so that's what I gave them.
I don't know why, nephew...
...and I hope I'm wrong...
...but it seems you're walking
near the monster pit...
...and if you fall in...
...and the monsters grab you,
they won't ever let you go.
What did you think of Gaby?
She's hot, right?
I bet you'd fuck her.
Yes.
Hey, Dad.
What's going on?
Are you all right?
Did you have
trouble sleeping?
What?
Where were you, Shorty?
Have you seen the news?
- Where were you, son?
- I asked Benjamin to stay for lunch.
The thieves knew the value
of the pieces...
...as they took the ones easiest
to transport and hide.
Some of the most
valuable of all time.
Pieces like the ones
I've just described...
...have been stolen
by criminals...
...probably linked to cultural
trafficking rings...
...that threaten every
museum in the world.
The National Institute of
Anthropology and History...
...warns Mexico of these thieves,
enemies of their past and heritage.
All Mexicans are called upon
to rally against...
...this act of shameful,
unpatriotic theft.
It's been one thing after
another, what a year!
How do you steal so many pieces?
Where were the guards?
- Culture's budget keeps being cut.
- Will you let me hear?
The value of these pieces is
inestimable in monetary terms.
Rather, their value is
cultural and artistic.
- In other news, earthquake rescue crews...
- Turn it off.
- They didn't say their worth.
- They did, they're priceless.
- You can't put a price on them.
- They don't know how.
How could they know?
It's our history.
Our heritage, our culture,
that's their only value.
Those who did it are miserable
bastards with no past or future.
I hope they rot in their own
curse, their own stupidity.
They are the dark shit
of this country.
When they catch them,
it is our solemn duty...
...to whip them
in the main square.
And drag their damned bodies
until they bleed out.
Sons of bitches!
What's wrong, Mom?
- Nothing.
- Are you crying?
No, no.
- What's wrong?
- Don't listen to him.
Come on, Wilson, they need to look
presentable if we want to sell them.
They weren't presentable
at the museum?
We need to fence them now.
Are you scared?
- Should we give them back?
- No, otherwise it's all wasted.
What if we go back
to the museum...
...and leave them at the coat check?
No one would notice.
What are we, clowns?
We'll take them to Bosco,
in Palenque, like we agreed...
...and he'll take us
to his client, that's it.
- That's it?
- Yes.
Juan thought about all the small gods
we had hidden in his closet.
Where are they now?
Do they still listen
to people's prayers?
Or did they leave them to their fate,
like they did to us?
Who were those men
who crafted those gods?
What was their life like?
And what would they think
about the way I live?
Juan! Wake up.
What?
Turn off the engine.
Where are you headed?
- Nowhere.
- Palenque.
Do you have ID?
Show it to me.
- Are you carrying marijuana?
- No.
- I wasn't talking to you, whitey.
Get out, we're searching the car.
Go stand over there.
Check everywhere.
What's in that bag?
Sergeant.
Do you collect handcrafts?
Yes.
You look familiar.
You're a famous actor,
aren't you?
Of course you are!
Can I get an autograph
for my girlfriend?
Sure.
[speaking Mayan]
- Good morning!
- Good morning.
Sit down, go on.
- How are you?
Hi, I'm Juan.
- Benjamin, from Satelite.
- Nice to meet you.
Do you know a guide here
named Bosco Huerta?
- No?
- How about "Chunuc"?
Ah! Yes, we know him.
- He was there earlier with a group.
- Who the hell is Chunuc?
Next stop will be
the Las Cruces site.
Wait, Chunuc!
I'm talking to you.
- Wait.
- We need to talk.
Unless you want to be
credited as the mastermind.
The what?
Me? The mastermind?
I have nothing to do
with this.
- You gave us the idea!
- Stop saying that.
- Stop saying that!
- For fuck's sake!
- Easy, Bosco.
- Juan has it all under control.
- Fucking psycho, you too.
You said: "Do something else,
don't be like our parents."
- But this isn't what I meant!
- It's normal to be scared.
- My hands are so delicate!
- They need to be moist, soaking wet.
Is that Scherezada Rios?
- That's a great movie.
- Juanito, I'm not helping you.
- I'm not joking.
- Chill, Bosco.
Sit down, sit.
You still haven't contacted
Mr. Gray, I assume.
- Graves.
- Well, look.
"Being a warrior is not
just about wishing it."
"It is an endless,
lifelong struggle."
Yes, yes.
"No one is born a warrior,
no one is born a commoner."
"It is we who become
one thing or the other."
Carlos Castaneda.
You can't use the master
to manipulate me.
That's a low blow,
even from you.
If you don't help us,
we'll go to Pepe Soto.
He'll fence them.
Go ahead, go to him.
You'll end up in jail...
- ...right next to him.
- So will you.
Me? In jail?
Pepe Soto
is the King Midas of shit.
Everything he touches
turns to shit.
Exactly.
That's why we're here,
and not with him.
- Get us in touch with Mr. Gray.
- Graves.
That's right, Graves.
We'll do the rest.
Even if I got ahold of him,
which I'm not doing...
...how will you talk him into
moving such hot pieces?
Hold this.
It's fucking beautiful.
- I know.
- Beautiful.
Are you going to help us?
What?
Nothing, man.
"Death is our eternal companion"
"Always to our left"
"An arm's distance away"
Fuck.
Holy shit.
So, what are you doing
with your share?
Those were the best days.
Sometimes, I even forgot
we had robbed the museum.
I liked to imagine that
blah, blah, blah.
"You felt its icy touch"
"The way you felt it today"
50 MILLION REWARD FOR HELP
RETRIEVING STOLEN ARTIFACTS
By then, the Interpol
was already on the case.
They were looking for
the Museum thieves.
Juan always quoted something
Hernan Cortes once said:
"I came here looking for gold,
not to plow the earth like a peasant."
He said he was finally
no longer afraid to die.
"Death is our eternal
companion...
Always behind us, to the left,
an arm's distance away.
Death is the only wise advisor
a warrior can count on.
When the warrior feels
he's about to be killed...
...he can turn to his death...
...and ask if it's true.
His death will tell him
he's wrong.
That nothing matters,
except for its touch.
His death will say;
'I haven't touched you yet'."
The Mayas who worked
near the pyramids told us...
...they often break in at night
to leave offerings for their dead.
Site employees always clear them
to keep it neat for the tourists.
I don't know for whom Juan's
offering was supposed to be.
I don't know if it was an offering,
or a way of apologizing...
...or some sort of reparation.
He never told me.
Juan.
It's done.
- Who?
- What do you mean "who"?
Frank Graves called back.
He wants to meet on Friday,
in Acapulco, we need to go.
Security was doubled at airports,
naval ports, and train stations...
...to keep the jewels
from being smuggled.
The Customs Office incorrectly
described the pieces to the outposts...
...claiming they were clay and stone,
when in fact they're gold and jade.
So, I'm the Mexican contact
for Mr....
- Mr. Quest.
- West.
- Yeah, Quest.
- Not Quest, West. All right?
Our boss, Mr. West has
businesses in the Caribbean.
- Let's not say that.
- No?
- Don't say a word.
- OK.
I'll do all the talking,
and when I signal...
...you take out the bait.
He needs to savor it.
- Those fuckers are like that.
- How?
Like that, like pedophiles.
And then can we go see
the cliff divers?
- Aren't you dressing up?
- I did.
What? No one told me we
had to dress like waiters.
I have to go home,
my dad is in the hospital.
Damn, Wilson.
That sucks.
Let's finish this
and get back tomorrow.
My dad is in the hospital,
I'm leaving.
Tomorrow, you'll be able to afford
any hospital for your dad.
Like Houston!
We'll get him there.
Think about it,
I'm only asking for one day.
- I can't, Juan.
- Don't do this to me, Wilson.
You can't abandon me,
you're my eagle commander!
- Damn it.
- I can't.
Listen, you shit!
If you abandon me,
I'll never forgive you!
Never!
Goddammit, you bastard!
Get in the fucking car!
Wilson! Hey!
Come here.
- What's that?
- Home.
- Right?
- Of course not.
It's Satelite, I'm telling you!
I love Acapulco.
These are Omar Robles
and Francisco Muñoz.
- Hey, Bosco! Come here.
- What, man?
- An Englishman?
- What?
We're giving the country's jewels
to a fucking Englishman?
They'll end up in
the fucking British Museum.
These fuckers don't care,
they don't even speak Spanish!
- Follow me.
- Dude!
- I'd like a rum and coke, too.
- Make it three!
It's not "Pre-Hispanic."
Meso-American or Maya,
which is what they are.
Ever heard of Belzoni?
Giovanni Belzoni?
He was an eccentric Italian,
a 19th century explorer.
In his London strongman shows
he'd lift 20 people at once.
They stole it.
Yes, Frank, I was there.
"There's no preservation
without plunder."
Frank, our boss, Mr. Quest,
is involved in heists...
...at the most prominent
museums in the world.
Europe, Asia, Africa,
the United States.
So don't be scared, Frank.
Mr. Quest is a professional.
What do you mean?
Frank, maybe you heard
this other story.
Rockefeller's plane was so heavy
from all the Maya stelae...
...they had stolen from us,
that it couldn't take off!
The law is strict when it comes
to archaeology, right?
Especially on foreigners.
They're fucking thieves,
like you.
Are we going back
to Mexico City?
I need to check up
on my dad.
Juan!
One of these.
What did she say?
Hello?
- Hello?
- Chiva.
- Where are you, idiot?
- Chiva, I need your help.
Dad's going to kill you.
Is he angry?
He reported the car as stolen.
Where are you, idiot?
But it wasn't stolen!
It's stolen, even if we know
who has the car.
I need to know the name of
Pepe Soto's club in Acapulco.
Why, you idiot?
Stop calling me idiot,
you hag!
What's the name
of the club in Acapulco?
What are you doing
in Acapulco, idiot?
I'm not!
What makes you think
I'm there?
"What makes you think..."
Dad will castrate you,
you fucking idiot.
Just give me the name!
Heaven's Gates.
Got it. Thanks, hag.
You're the only one of the four
I like, don't tell anyone.
Visiting hours at the hospital
start at eight o'clock.
Juan?
Juan.
How will we get there
if you don't know where it is?
Remember the book
Journey to Ixtlan?
The Castaneda one?
Remember when Don Juan
shows them how to stop the world?
Don't do that, Juan.
Don't worry.
Don't worry, It's all good.
Just be chill.
- Juan!
- Just breathe.
Go with the flow, man.
Just breathe.
We'll be with Pepe soon.
We'll get an advance for the pieces
and we'll go back home.
Turn on the lights!
Holy shit! Oh, fuck!
You fucking asshole!
He hit us, asshole!
Turn them on!
Stop the car, asshole!
- Turn on the lights!
- There, there.
- Pull over now! Pull over!
- What for?
Stop the car.
Where are you going?
Where are you going, idiot?
What are you doing?
- Where are you going?
- Fuck you, to Mexico!
- Get back here.
- Stop it!
Don't start with this!
You'll end up crying.
I'm done following you.
I'm done!
Without me, you're just
a stupid dog groomer...
...who wipes his dad's asshole!
Listen, you piece of shit.
I took the blame when you nearly
blinded Toño Juarez, remember?
They would've put you
in a mental hospital!
I'm your only friend!
Do you understand?
Let go of me!
Will you be calm?
Let go of me, asshole!
Fuck off, dead-weight!
I'm better off without you!
START THE ACTION
AT THE SEA!
- We should've studied music.
- You think?
We'd have a kick ass band,
and we'd leave this place.
Floyd didn't study music.
Floyd's not one person,
it's four.
- I mean, you don't need to study.
- Or say dumb shit every time.
To leave this place, I mean.
- Bowie.
- He did study.
That guy did study music.
Haven't we gone through
this place before?
- Obviously.
- Where are we going?
We're just driving around.
You got somewhere to be?
- That's the point of driving around.
- Passing the same place over and over?
- That's Satelite-folk's problem.
- That they go in circles?
That they can't enjoy life.
- And you?
- Me? I try to.
- I mean are you Satelite-folk?
- No.
- What are they like, then?
- They're so tired from work...
...they'd rather watch TV
than be with their family.
What's on TV tires them,
so they go to bed more tired.
Their dreams tire them, too.
They look like crap, so tired.
And one day, just like that,
they die from exhaustion.
What if you stop
turning the wheel?
- We stop going in circles.
- We go in a straight line.
- We crash into the light post.
- And we die.
Then we wake up and realize
we're still driving in circles.
Or... we could do
something different.
Like what?
Like nicking something.
Nicking something?
You mean stealing?
- Why not?
- Why yes?
Because I'm sick of waiting for
something to happen, aren't you?
Would stealing make
something happen?
Do you have a better idea?
That's what I thought.
So, what would we nick?
This car?
No way! This car belongs
to my family.
- So, what then?
- We'll figure it out later.
Excuse me!
Good evening!
Do you know a place called
Heaven's Gates?
- Excuse me?
- Heaven's Gates?
Heaven's gates
are closed to you.
Just kidding!
Heaven's Gates
is that way!
- Thank you!
- You got it.
HEAVEN'S GATES
That's Scherezada, right?
- From the movies?
- What else can I get you?
It's her, right?
It has to be.
Hey, man. Come here.
Tell Pepe Soto that Lazy Juan
is here for him.
I don't know him.
Pepe Soto.
That guy right there.
Your boss.
That guy hasn't been
around here in a while.
- Anything else?
- Can I have my money back?
Yeah, shake it, come here.
Come jingle those coins
in my face!
Where are you going?
Come dance with me!
- Leave her alone!
- Old hag!
- Respect the artist!
- Go look after your grandkids, bitch!
Why are you dancing here
if you're gonna be a bitch about it?
- Is this how you treat your sisters?
- Mind your fucking business.
- Apologize to her.
- Fuck you.
And now, a fight.
Enough, assholes.
Here is your fucking
white knight, Eugenia.
Take him out the back,
or they'll kill him.
Wait, my bag.
My bag, my bag!
- Hey, where's my bag?
- It's here, kid.
Listen, you can't come here
and get into a fight...
...and think that nothing
will happen to you.
It's not a soap opera set,
this is the state of Guerrero.
They disrespected you,
Scherezada.
That's so nice.
What a moron!
Why do you play the hero?
You're too small for that.
- Why aren't you at a club?
- Scherezada Rios is not there.
Don't call me that.
My name is Eugenia.
- Eugenia?
- Yeah.
I had no idea.
Don't worry about it,
why would you know?
I've seen The Hard Life of an
Easy Woman a million times.
Another fan.
Yeah, so what?
- I hear you're looking for Pepe.
- Yes.
Pepe died last year.
What?
Yeah, he was killed.
Fuck.
It'll be six months now.
He owed a lot of money.
He was mixed up in things,
way above his head.
- What did you want with him?
- Help.
From Pepe?
You must be in deep shit
if you need help from Pepe.
- Can I use your phone?
- Sure.
50 MILLION REWARD FOR HELP
RETRIEVING STOLEN ARTIFACTS
Do you sell handcrafts?
They're not handcrafts.
The stuff inside that bag
is worth millions of dollars...
...and nothing at all.
When he was alive...
...this place was the best.
It was the best one.
People fought to get in.
Say that again.
What?
I said people fought to get in.
People fought to get in.
What?
My love!
Wait, I have an idea!
Know what a zarahuato is?
- No.
- A monkey that goes like this.
That's right,
now a bit of this.
There we go.
Wait, wait! Like a monkey!
Yes, Scherezada.
Schere...
Honestly, I've dreamt of you
after every one of your movies.
I have dedicated so many
nighttime thoughts to you.
No, I won't tell you what I did.
What's the point?
Yeah, that's right.
Dance for me.
Good morning!
Have you seen a red bag?
Are you sure?
A red bag around here?
I'm a fucking idiot!
I'm so stupid!
What a fucking idiot!
I get dizzy thinking about how close
those pieces came to being lost forever.
I think of all the things that might've
disappeared without anyone knowing.
All the things that
could have never been.
And yet, there they are.
One time, we crashed the car
and Juan's dad confessed...
...how close they came
to having him aborted.
Juan always said he wished
they had done it.
What do you think
they're arguing about?
Who jumps last.
He gets the best tips.
We have to hide, Wilson.
We can't stay here.
Are you listening to me?
My father died.
- No!
- And I wasn't there for him.
Benjamin...
...I'm so sorry.
I'm truly sorry.
And Pepe Soto?
I couldn't find him.
Where would we go?
We'd disappear for a while.
And the pieces?
They'll disappear
along with us.
Dad.
Mom.
Dad?
I'm leaving.
- Where were you?
- What are you doing, son?
Where have you been?
Are you OK?
I'm leaving, Mom.
- I just wanted to say goodbye.
- They're looking for you.
The police were here
a few times.
- Where were you?
- What did you do, huh?
What did you do?
- I fucked up.
- What did you do, Juan?
What have you done, honey?
What have you done?
The officer said you're a suspect
in the museum robbery.
I told him he was wrong.
That you gave us
a hard time...
...that we struggled with you...
...but that you were
no thief.
You lied, Dad.
I am.
It was me.
I did it.
Stupid son of a bitch.
Stupid son of a bitch!
Dumb son of a bitch!
You dumb moron!
Son of a bitch!
Why did you do it?
Why... did you do it?
I'm just no good.
It's not your fault.
I'm leaving.
- You won't have to see me again.
- Where will you go?
They're looking for you
everywhere.
I don't know.
I'll disappear.
I'll never bother you again.
What was it you wanted?
Was it money?
You have money.
Always.
You have never ever
wanted for anything.
You've always had
everything.
Why did you do it?
Why?
Did you want to impress us?
We're impressed, Juan.
We're truly impressed.
Juan, no...
Juan.
We won't take long.
Dad!
What is it?
- What are you doing Juan?
- Leave the two bags.
Wait for me outside.
I'll be right back.
Juan!
What you're seeing here...
...is the empty display cases
of the relics of the Maya room.
Authorities claim that a group
of professional traffickers...
...of about twenty men
pulled off the heist.
They are experts
in robbing art galleries...
...of the highest caliber,
and connections in Africa...
...Asia and Europe.
When the museum reopened
after the robbery...
...more people came
than ever before.
Everyone wanted to see
the empty cases.
That fat intellectual guy,
the one with the cats...
...said that was the robbers'
gift to Mexico:
The reminder that no one knows
what they have until it's gone.
No touching.
Pakal was one of the most
important rulers of Palenque.
THIS PIECE IS A REPLICA
OF THE ORIGINAL
Hieroglyphic records tell us he rose
to the throne when he was twelve.
And he died well into
his eighties.
The mask and the whole
funeral attire are important...
...because they weren't plundered,
the tomb wasn't opened until 1952.
I said no touching!
So, the funeral attire was found
exactly like the Mayas placed it...
...when Pakal's body
was laid to rest.
Attention. R-3.
Attention.
Maya room. R-3.
Suspect headed
to the central courtyard.
Sometimes I wonder...
...what would've happened
if Juan hadn't separated from me.
Sometimes I wonder
why he did it.
Why we did
everything we did.
But then I remember
what Juan used to say...
...about how only the person who did
something knows why they did it.
And more often than not,
not even them.
Freeze!
And if they do know...
...they won't tell you anyway.
Juan said if I ever told our story,
I shouldn't tell the truth.
I asked him why.
"The truth?" he said.
"Why ruin a good story
with the truth?"